啊！
首先咧，我哋誒歡迎今日出席會議嘅誒代表，咁誒。
咁其實上訴法庭咧亦都曾經喺案例入邊解釋過啦，例子咧就並不是長盡無遺嘅。係咁呢啲補充資料畀議員參考，多謝主席。
好，唔該曬誒法律顧問誒，而家咧我哋就誒去到誒繼續審議條文嘅部分啦。咁喺呢度咧，我哋誒。
嘅附屬法例嘅，咁換言之咧，第十五號法律公告嘅附註嘅用意咧，就係僅供讀者備知，就冇其他作用嘅，就唔係好似規則入邊噉嘅條文有法律效力嘅。
誒自上次誒知知道現在咧，噉我哋誒法律顧問咧想誒回應一下誒委員誒對上一次嘅一啲誒關注點，噉我而家將時間交畀法律顧問先，唔該。
早晨誒夠時間咧，亦都夠誒法定人數，噉我哋可以準時開會啦。歡迎各位出席誒今日嘅與實施無紙證券市場制度相關的六項附屬法例小組誒委員會嘅會議。
今日有誒財富局嘅何兆康誒副秘書長朱浩誒助理秘書長證監會嘅梁仲賢誒執行董事誒穆嘉林誒高級總監同埋其他幾位嘅誒證監會同埋律政司嘅代表，歡迎你哋先。
首先就處理誒，自上次開會至今咧，就秘書處收到一份嘅意見書，噉啊，已於昨日咧發畀委員㗎啦。咁亦都誒要求誒當局咧作出書面嘅回應，待收到回應之後咧，會誒再發翻畀委員誒去參考嘅。
上次誒喺上次會議嗰度咧，噉我知道委員關注到咧第十五號法律公告底下咧第二條咧就有啲定義使用咗例子咧作為輔讀工具嘅，即係Readers A啦。噉我希望就誒呢份法律公告入邊一啲附註同埋例子咧，就提供補充資料畀議員參考嘅。咁首先咧就附註而言嘅話咧。
係，主席。
之前咧，亦都。
Schedule One.
一條比較有關注嘅，噉我哋可以再掘深少少嘅。噉啊，而家時間交畀局方啦，嚇，唔該。
Of the SFO, well we're we're going to add it by way of the amendment ordinance, and if you look at Schedule One, the addition there, it's it links back to Section 101AA.
The second question was about the definition of prescribed securities and participating securities. So the definition of prescribed securities is actually in.
所以，which are listed or to be listed on a recognised stock market，所以那係定義。OK，好唔該主席，即係即係有有會有解釋㗎啦，放心啊，噉我就唔該曬主席。係誒，仲有位誒係一位誒簡維敏議員。
咁另外咧，誒主席，我都想請問一下咧，prescribed securities咧，嗱上次就好誒有誒，即係阿Miss McCadden都有解釋過咧，誒prescribed securities同埋participating securities嘅分別。
咁根據翻證券及期貨條例附表一嘅第十三條咧，咁喺該條例入邊咧嘅附註咧就只供備知嘅啫，並無立法效力嘅。咁而誒憑藉啦誒翻附表一第十二條咧，剛剛提到第十三條咧，亦都會係適用於咧喺證券及期貨條例底下咧定立。
咁第二點咧，就關於誒條文入邊咧例子嘅公誒例子嘅效力嘅。咁誒留意到啦，頭先所講到附表一第十三條嗰個誒地位條文咧，個statute clause咧就淨係澄清咗附著嘅地位嘅啫。咁例子咧就唔係受到嗰條文所規範嘅。咁所以喺冇適用嘅地位條文嘅情。
況底下咧，例子咧就會係視為誒規則嘅一部分，噉就會係同條文本身咧有相同嘅效力嘅。咁誒就只係我哋都會以前咧同證監會方面咧溝通過，咁都知識咧證監會對呢個睇法就冇異議嘅。噉就住例子咧，仲有多個補充資料嘅。噉就係關於例子咧，其實係咪長盡無遺啦？係咪exhaustive嘅？咁
誒因應翻對上一次誒嘅會議咧，噉啊，邀請政府當局咧，由誒證券及其貨無紙證券市場規則第三條誒開始逐項誒介紹條文。誒咁誒嗰個委員如果有意去作出提問咧，就可以禁制誒。
誒連問連答咧就四分鐘。咁審議上述四項嘅附屬法例時咧，請政府當局同埋委員咧使用法律事務部而以而備嘅誒標明修訂文本立法會C.B.括一三七一括零四至零七號文件嘅誒正式開始。
提醒誒誒，希望誒誒局方同埋證監會作出嗰個誒逐條審議嘅時候咧，都誒繼續去尊重，即係逐條去做啦。咁當然每一逐條去審議嗰時候咧，就未必每一條都需要即係誒好過度詳盡。咁但係當委員對嗰一
Thank you, Mr. Chairman. So last time we completed the clause by clause review up to the end of clause two, so I will start from clause three, which is the clause on evidencing and transfer of title without instrument. So the reason for this clause is because there is a provision in the primary legislation, section one.
101 AAC， which talks about how securities may be evidenced and transferred without instrument， and it refers to this being possible in the manner that's set out in the rules. So this clause three is intended to supplement that one， and essentially it says。
That for evidencing it would be by a record in the register of holders, as described in Rule 11, which we will come to in due course. And for the purposes of transfer, it will be by a specified request that complies with Rules 13 or 14. And again,我誒我哋誒誒時間交畀誒江玉峯。
connected.
誒。
Would like.
比較清晰啲而家嚇。
for。
You can look at.
for the C.O. for the company's ordinance.
但我可以帶你到相關條文，如果。
但係可唔可以而家帶我哋去睇翻個相關嘅條文？Yeah, sure. So, um.
主席，你認為係係咪我理解，即係喺二零二一年嗰個已經實施嗰個，就已經誒處理咗啦啊？
誒，我原來都係即係同阿江議員差唔多個問題嚇，因為我想知道一零一A A C咧係點樣規定啊？嗯。
有冇補充係？Yeah, so actually, apart from Section 101AAC, we have actually amended the substantive provisions of say the Companies Ordinance, the Stamp Duty Ordinance and
議員有個提問，係主席，我想請問一下咧，就誒一零一A A C一咧，係唔係而家新嘅誒修改會加進去嘅咧？一零一A A C一，因為我我睇我睇過，即係而家嗰條即係ordinance就冇呢個section啦。
但係咧嗱，分別就當然喺四，我可以明白啦。第四條嗰度，但係其實我睇暈曬咧喺呢條條例咧。如果我哋去到誒mention啊prescribe securities嘅次數一定係比participating securities多，我想請問一下有冇一個好清晰嘅定義咧，就有關。
prescribed securities。唔該主席。係。點解冇？Okay, thank you for that question. So the first question was whether 101 AAC is in the current legislation or is in the amendment ordinance. So it is actually in the amendment ordinance, and it will come into effect together with the entire USM related legislation.
Section one one hundred and one AA, which is the heading of which is what are prescribed securities, and the definition there is basically it's securities which fall within a class of description specified in Schedule three A. So Schedule three A again is a new schedule that is added by the amendment ordinance, and also.
如果即係會係喺個今次喺個amendment係會出現嚇，即係喺我哋呢度係咪嚟緊有後邊會講到咁？我想睇翻嗰個具體嘅條款啊！啊，即係如果呢一條係已經喺原來個條例咧，我原先嘅諗法就係話可唔可以噉樣講嚇？即係如果你嗰個。
條例已經有呢一條，譬如個條例係規定一定要有個instrument，一定要有紙本先至可以作為有效嘅證明嘅話咧，噉我嘅question就係你噉樣用個附屬法例去改得唔得嘅咧？噉樣嚇，咁所以如果係會改嗰個ordinance itself嘅話咧，係會改個條條例咧，咁不如我哋應該睇埋會比。
The fund companies will be amending the rules that that's part of the subsidiary legislation. So for the companies, there is a section in on transfer which currently talks about transfers having to be by way of an instrument of transfer. So we have amended those provisions to say that they can be by way of an instrument of transfer or
啊！
and the amendment to section 150, subsection one.
是 prescribed securities， and then what is required is either a proper instrument of transfer or a specified request.
splits the original provision. So the original provision talks about the need to deliver a proper instrument of transfer.
So if you, I don't know if you have the amendment ordinance to hand. So it's section thirty four.
O.K.江玉寬議員，主席，我想請問法律顧問，你可唔可以再重讀一次你嗰條二零二一嗰條法例咧？
三， of the amendment ordinance， which amends section 150 of the companies ordinance.
附屬嘅嘅誒法例啦嚇，咁明白嚇。因為如果唔係咧，我哋而家指向嗰個大例，如果冇呢個基礎喺度咧，就唔肯定你修訂啲條，即係呢啲rules嘅時候咧，嗰啲規例咧，可唔可以噉樣講嚇？嚇唔該曬。
一指定 request， and then that provision is again linked to the subsidiary legislation. So those amendments to the companies ordinance and and there's an equivalent amendment to the stamp duty ordinance for unit trusts, units and the unit trust. So those amendments were passed as part of the amendment ordinance. So they are already there, and that ordinance has been.
所以那條條文已經被修改，要被分成兩部分。一，處理那些不是指配的股份，所以那些股份不在USM的範圍內。然後，那部分會繼續要求一個轉移的工具。然後，第二部分談論那些股份。
係啊，主席，可唔可以請法律顧問確認一下，即係而家局方解釋咧，即係話頭先讀出嚟嘅條文咧，就已經生效咗㗎啦，即係唔係喺今次呢一個修例嗰度嘅嚇？係法律顧問，係多謝議員嘅提問嘅。噉係嘅，誒當時就會誒嗰個誒條例咧，就叫做二零二一年證券及期貨。
生效咧。
Okay.
Okay, so I proceed then to close for.
所以如果 look at clause four one。
我睇佢，那close three is。
投資者會 be able to hold and transfer without paper documents.
also cease to become to be prescribed securities.
Not being earlier than the date on which the issuer has taken certain steps, and those steps.
係，正啱我。Will all come into effect at the same time? The entire regime. Okay, guys, thank you.
好，證監會可以繼續。Sorry, um, just for members' reference, we've put the title up on the screen. If you are interested to see it.
所以，因為重要性。的這個概念，它重要，要非常清楚，當證券成為參與的，和當他們停止參與。和所以，條文四，條文四，主要嘗試做呢。
涉及公司法例修訂條例嘅噉就喺二零二一年嘅時候咧六月誒就制定咗嘅噉就當時嗰個條誒條例修訂條例咧就係正如誒頭先誒證監會嗰邊所講啦，噉就為咗喺香港設立翻呢個無紙證券市場咧，定定咗一個大嘅法律框架嘅噉就喺一啲主要嘅條文咧就已經喺誒證誒。
誒證券及期貨條例啦，同埋公司條例啦等等嘅條例度反映咗出嚟嘅。咁而家我哋今次處理呢啲附屬法例咧，就係喺當時定立嘅法律框架底下咧，再作出嘅一啲誒比較實際操作嘅規則嘅。多謝主席。即係換句話嚟講，應該二零二一年已經處理咗誒，不過而家後續就係再進一步。
部嘅各方面嘅細節噉樣咯，嚇係係多謝主席同埋法律顧問嚇。咁呢個就有助我哋理解嚇。一嚟咧就係二零二一年嘅時候咧，我哋當時咪議員啦嚇，噉就即係一嚟咧就係即係呢一個方面嚇。你修定咗噉，但係亦都係我哋討論政策嘅時候都有提過嘅。即係二一年做咗，但係到到今天其實都四年啦，噉我哋先至改翻呢啲。
法例個名稱咧係《二零二一年證券及期貨及公司法例括弧修訂條例》，噉就係誒第二零二一年嘅第十七號條例嚟嘅。噉就喺二零二一年嘅六月十一號喺刊誒憲報刊登嘅。咁呢條條例咧就尚未實施嘅，噉就。
會係誒，即係會係由翻誒局方嗰邊以誒憲報公告嘅形式去實施嘅。多謝誒，多謝議員嘅提問，多謝主席。尚未實施嘅咁唔怪得之，我晚咁睇嗰條主席，我晚咁睇而家條啲現有嗰啲法例都冇一零一a a c提，所以唔該曬你嘅清晰，唔好意思。噉我想請問一下，咁嗱呢一條條。
例，我哋而家審緊嘅成日講一零一A A C又Prescribe Securities啦，嚇用呢啲字，基本上就喺嗰條通過咗嗰條條例冇問題。咁但係我就想問，咁咁到時會唔會同時間生效嘅咧？嗱，因為頭先講通過咗，未生效啊。噉我想請問係咪同一時間會？
所以這是條文，解釋什麼參與參與證券是什麼。而如我提到，當我們談論定義條文時，這是一個在USM規則中很重要的一個概念，因為是參與證券，即參與證券，會會。
essentially clause four one says that prescribed securities becomes participating securities on their participation date, and they cease to become participating securities when they cease to be listed. So the reason for them to cease to be participating when they cease to be listed is because once they cease to be listed, they will actually
啊！
但taking into account the particular needs of the U.S.M. regime.
O.K.可以繼續，誒，正交。
by an approved securities registrar, so when it is.
So moving then to subclause three, which is the definition of participation date.
相關要發布將會被設定在listing規則中，所以the issuer會有要發布一個日期，符合listing規則。
V approved securities registrar. It follows that the UNSRT system is one that is operated by that ASR.
at that point would not necessarily tie with any particular UN SRT system. So the concept there is that the issuer must find a system, so to speak.
There is a definition for UNSRT system in the in the 2021 orders. In the 2021 orders, yeah. And how about the approved securities register? It's also there. Okay, that's very good then. Thank you.
所以 sub clause one essentially says that the register can be in English or Chinese. Sub clause two talks about what the register must contain. So it's the usual things like name and address, the holder when when the person becomes a holder and when they cease to be a holder.
所以，starting first with clause five， which is the obligation for the issuer to keep a register of holders， this clause is cast broadly by reference to section 627 of the Companies Ordinance， which imposes an obligation on all Hong Kong companies to keep a register of members。
嗯，moving down，停一停。誒，江玉歡議有問題，係我有問題喺呢個二B一嗰度咧，想請問一下嗱。呢度你有提過U N S R T system嚇，冇問題。噉我想請問點解喺呢一度你唔會用corresponding U N S
SRT system，而你就噉樣用UNSRT system咧，因為呢個嗱，如果喺呢條條例啫，我唔知會唔會喺二零二一嗰度有啦。你依個冇define嘅喎，你只係有define個corresponding UNSRT system。呢個第一個問題，第二個問題又想請問一下approved securities registrar。
依個請問有冇定義嘅咧？喺邊度有咧？嚇，唔該。
And when he has found that system, then because the the paragraph two it talks about the approved securities registrar, so the approved securities registrar would provide the connection to the UNSRT system. Because if you look at paragraph one, it talks about a UNSRT system operate operated.
主主席，我有追問誒，對唔住，我完全respect我，我明白啊。Miss McAdam舉講過嚟講講嗰個問題，但係咧喺法例嚟計，我一定要有一個definition先得㗎。係我完全明白你嘅解釋，very good，但係我我我唔能夠下下冇一個definition。
所以，essentially， the participation date is the is the date that is published under Rule Two A, which is the date that the issuer publishes as being the date that it becomes a participating that its securities become participating securities. So this obligation.
If I may, then move on to clause five. So maybe just before going into clause five, I'd just give an overview that the next next sections deal with a separate part, which is the part on the register of holders. So a number of these provisions we've actually drawn by reference to equivalent co provisions, and
發生以後。
是收屍以後。
對。
係，啊，證監會係。
O.K. 啊，下一位誒，譚學勤議員。
是不是？這就要求這個發行人每天。
都會有在這個登記冊裏面進行變動。
還是什麼時間要備妥這個登記冊呢？
所以，那There is no misunderstanding. It will not be relying just on the name.
誒，謝謝主席。這個，因為這個，誒，發行人登記冊嘛，這個，誒，持有人的日期。
是，所以有個清楚的紀錄在成員名冊裡，面，有個特定的證券由特定的成員持有，係未證實的形狀。
誒，就是每某一個人持有這個證券的持有人的日期，然後呢，任何人不再持有這個證券的日期，啊，那就是説這個每天的交易。
Subclause three is the unique one for USM because what we require is that the register of holders must also include must also indicate whether the securities in question are held in uncertificated form and how many securities are held in uncertificated form, and the reason for
係誒，我哋誒吳傑莊議員有個提問嚇。係主席誒，我睇到呢度咧個register of holders咧就主要係名同埋誒地址啦。咁identify一個人噉，其實誒足唔足夠咧？其實因為而家會唔會有啲同名啊，或者一啲假地址啊？會唔會多啲？譬如一啲證件號碼啊，甚至係一啲submission話。
一啲保密check information，因為而以前實物揸住喺手都會穩陣啊嘛，咁而家in case唔知喺邊度，噉佢會擔心會唔會呢方面，可能之前條例講咗，但我想了解下個rationale係點，唔該。係，請問有冇啲？Yeah, so thank you for that question. So, um, we did consider that as well about the need for personal, personal identity.
身份信息，我們需要個人身份信息，為ASR運作的目的，為ASR運作，執行其功能。但我們不認為將其納入登記冊是適當的，因為登記冊對公眾開放檢查，在許多情況下，這是主要原因。但註冊官。
The ASR will have that information, and that information will be very important for it to ensure that securities are passed to the right person when it affects transfers. And when transfers are effected, there will be in the message there will be sufficient information to clearly identify who's the transferor and who's the transferee.
好啦，去到第八嗰度，主席。
嗱，雖然咧，你就頭先啊，Miss McCadden就解釋。
嚇！咁點解對於物業我哋嘅處理就見到曬身份證嘅喎，全部嚇乜都地址乜都見到曬嘅。
所以係兩種唔同嘅嘢，交易係係一個唔同嘅嘢，完全同註冊轉移喺成員名冊嘅註冊係唔同嘅嘢。
誒，江玉虎議員，主席，我有三條問題咧。第一咧就係頭先啊吳傑莊問嗰條問題，好好喎。
可以唔可以唔可以損毀啊？但係要keep到去最少十年。咁如果嗰個人keep八年咧，噉佢冇冇犯法嘞噃？唔使罰啊，係咪咧？啊呢個可唔可以解釋一下咧？
請問一下啦，我就喺度諗緊，咦？咁如果收唔齊嗰啲資料咧，咁有冇咩情況喺呢條條例嗰度講咧？嚇，緊係有，緊係有情景係你收唔足資料嘅，係咪？
of the CICAS nominee， so the register of holders does not record all of those transfers because not all investors will be withdrawing their securities out of CICAS and registering it into their own name.
要被Entered in a register of members. This is not only the case in Hong Kong, but also in the cases of other jurisdictions where we have looked at their laws. We haven't seen anything which talks about putting personal identification of the registered holder in the public register.
名啊嗰啲，咁點解會同股票會有一個？即係我想睇下一個政策嘅原則點解咧？可其實嚇係咪純粹話安全咁安全啲咁咪物業嗰啲人咪好唔安全咯？如果咁呢個第一個問題。嗱第二個問題，我想請教一下咧，就喺第五嗰度。
即係應該嚟講就係分開喺中央結算處理嘅，同埋非中央結算處理嘅。咁所以好似啱啱所講，誒，即係平時日常交易嗰啲就喺中央結算，噉佢就係一個好似誒nominee形式噉樣，就所以就唔會牽涉到個問題。我咁理解。
Yeah, thank you for that question. So actually, trading is separate from transfer. So when you trade on the stock exchange, you will settle within two days. You have a T plus two settlement cycle. So when you trade, you are trading securities that are already inside CACs and already registered in the name of the SE.
嗱，因為咧畀公眾睇到，所以就唔需要有咁多資料。噉我自己就突然間諗起，咁又唔係買賣物業喺個land register嚟緊。我哋新嘅land registration嗰條就算amendment ordinance好多嘢都會擺在一個public record嗰度嘅噃。咁嗱，大家同樣都係一個asset啊。
嗱，第五嗰度咧就講法韓人喺收到足以第咩第二第三款嘅詳情，即係足以可以令到佢哋入到嗰啲詳情嘅時候咧，佢就要喺合理地、切實可行嘅範圍內，盡快就要即係啊，將嗰啲情情形咧，即係嗰嗰啲詳情咧，就入落去嗰個登記冊。噉我想。
第八嗰度咧，嗱，呢度就有講到啦。如果咧第一同埋第五項咧違規嘅時候咧，就會罰罰㗎嚇要罰。噉我肯問啦，咁點解第六違規唔使罰咧？可第六五嘅五嘅六嗱，五嘅六就係話咧，所有嘅entry都要keep最少十年嘅唔可。
係，真係冇嘢。係。Okay, thank you for those questions. So, starting first with the question about the land registry, like I said at the outset, these provisions are cast by reference to the Companies Ordinance. As far as I'm aware, Companies Legislation does not require personal identification information.
嗯。
and the realm requirements for USN.
我 suppose it's a fair comment. Just speaking from a
provisions where they are assisting the issuer in carrying out their obligations.
所以，again，subsection six is based on the company's ordinance. I think the way I read subsection six is that it's a
requirements or regulations which are not necessary to USM and which have much broader and fundamental impact. So for that reason, we have not included it in the
my own personal view, my expectation is that probably transfers of land are just not as common as transfers of securities, so perhaps there is a greater need for
它係一個條款，唔需要破壞，或者只係允許破壞。破壞完之後，10年，所以其實證券登記處可以繼續保留紀錄超過10年。所以你的問題係：，如果他們破壞紀錄少於10年，
公開披露， in the context of of of property, I I I'm just speculating. But the reason we have not included it in our legislation is because we have tried to stick as closely as possible to the companies' legislation. We don't want the USM regime to be creating things or introducing concepts or introducing.
其其他個兩點。Sorry, yes. So the other question was on subsection five, and what happens if the information received is incomplete? The transfer request will be refused. That happens today as well. So for example, if a person comes along with an instrument of transfer, he doesn't come along with the
Correct number of share certificates, his transfer will just be refused. He will he will be asked to go away, and I think that's reasonable and acceptable. As to your question about the offence provision, why is it not an offence for subsection six?
即係譚議員問嗰個嗰個問題。
非實物嗰啲股票，即係無紙嗰啲股票咧，其實都有兩類方式持有，直接持有同埋透過券商持有嚇。係啊，多謝啊梁生頭先嘅解釋嚇。咁如果佢直接持有同埋透過券商去持有嘅話咧，對嗰個名冊有咩分別啊？
而嗰啲股票係喺中央結算嘅系統裏邊嘅時候咧，咁嗰啲股票嘅轉讓咧就唔會涉及改個股東名冊，因為嗰啲股票一個持有人就係中央結算代理人。所以我想解解釋清楚，即係將來喺無紙化嗰個環境之下咧，其實。
實體化同埋咧，佢又將佢唔實體化，有呢個選項㗎嘛？噉嘅時候會對嗰個名冊有咩影響？嚇，有咩變動？嚇，唔該。係或者正佳，我可以一路解釋，一路繼續誒講嗰個條文，係咪？係咪誒？梁生想誒表達嚇？
We we haven't made it an offence here, but I guess in practical terms, because the register of holders will actually be managed by the share registrar or the ASR, and the ASR will be regulated by us, and we will be able to take regulatory action against them if they breach any of the.
But we haven't made it an offence for that reason，主席係係簡短嘅，已經講咗。簡短簡短誒，主席，我想講翻翻去諗諗，就係有關嗰個身份證明嗰度，因為咧嗱，其實而家嘅即係騙案好多啊，主席。我希望就算你唔係話寫曬成個身份證號碼出嚟，可唔可以其實有四個字母咧嚇？
即係我自己覺得呢一個都係for scam，因為嚟緊嘢要無紙化咧，我都擔心，我唔知道啲第日嗰啲網上嗰啲嚇啲scam會點樣。第二樣嘢就係關於嗰個regulatory action，關於十年嗰樣嘢。嗱，雖然頭先啊Miss McAdam講佢係可以做regulatory action嘅，如果佢哋好快咁destroy曬啲嘢，但係我覺得對於消費者員，
投資者而言，其實十年你擺得喺度係一定有佢嘅作用嘅。噉係咪應該都要對於投資者而言要有啲保障，而唔係話from S F C去到take regulatory action咁簡單咧，都可以有一個機會畀佢哋係知道佢要佢要遵守嘅，佢有一個即係罰則先得咧。我呢個提議啫，嚇想各方翻嚟諗一諗，唔該主席。
好係誒，請請局方去考慮。誒，下一位係簡維敏議員啊。好，唔該，主席。誒，主席，我呢個問題咧就係誒計頭先阿譚議員嗰個問題嚇。誒，我哋知道即係嗰個交易，同埋咧即係去誒將嗰個轉名嚇，即係所謂。
係喺呢個register嗰度咧，係兩件事啦嚇，即係你trading之後仲有T加二，跟跟住就再如果係視乎你喺seekers定係拎出嚟啦。噉我哋而家就係正正咧喺傾個政策嘅時候咧，就係話令到誒大眾或者係股民咧，佢可以有一個選項，就係咧唔一定咧就係好似而家嘅做法。
喺喺誒C-Class nominee，即係喺nominee嗰度嚇，噉佢就可以拎出嚟，即係唔一定喺個代理人幫佢持股啦。咁所以我哋而家有五括弧三呢度嚇，即係五二咧，其實可以話不嬲，你個都係咁㗎啦，即係個股東名冊都係要包括名嘅地址。咁但係如果有uncertified uncertificated嘅話，
話咧，即係話U.S.M.我哋而家成個機制擺落去咧，就係話要將佢，如果佢唔用有紙啦，係諗用無紙化嘅時候咧，就需要有呢一個機制喺度，就擺翻去幾多個單位，然後咧就幾多噉就放咗落去嚇。咁所以呢一度咧，其實亦都係要結合埋求先。
喺嗰個誒轉讓之後，而有容許佢做呢個機制，因為rules three同埋即係三同埋四咧，係要一齊睇嚇。當然，我哋頭先快咗少少，其實未講第四嘅，或者可唔可以趁呢個機會講三同埋四嘅時候咧，就要講講個操作。即係如果佢係material嚟，即係話佢將佢實。
誒誒，主席，我我想誒解釋少少啫。啊，頭先阿簡議員嗰個問題咧，我想解釋少少。其實將來個無紙化嗰個操作咧，就即係我哋上一次有講到啦。投資者可以繼續有實物股票啦，但係投資者亦都可以選擇用誒無紙嘅形式，即係unspecified form去誒持有個股票啦。咁但係佢用無紙嘅方式。
持有股票咧，佢都有兩個方法嘅。一個方法就係佢喺個誒核准登證券登記公司度開一個我我哋上次講個U.S.I個户口就持有啦。另一個方法咧，佢可以透過啲券商同埋銀行咧，持有一個非實物嘅股票都可以嘅。咁所以嗰喺個誒中央結算個系統裏邊咧，其實佢。
嗯。
and do what is.
That actually are imposed on the issuer.
and they're complaining that they're getting all this material that they shouldn't be getting.
The sheriffs are under an obligation. We have actually got a code of conduct.
所以，一啲嘅嘢，我們有睇過，係呢個問題，即係地址唔係最新。
Ada咧，如果真真真係都收唔到嘅話咧，人哋咧有投訴，咁咧後屘咧唔唔知點處理嘅嚇，就係呢個咧係誒，可唔可以解釋一下？係，證監會。
咧就如果話呢個誒持有人咧個地地址嘅話咧，如果佢搬咗係嘛咁咧，你你普通嘅誒信件係寄唔到嘅，寄唔到嘅話咧。
Thank you for that question. So this is actually an issue that's currently faced by share registrars as well, where the registered holders they've moved on, but they haven't updated their records with the issuer.
佢會將來會一啲股票咧都係非實物嘅，嗰啲非實物嘅股票咧，其實有一部分咧亦都會係投資者係透過誒券商同銀行咧去持有嘅。咁所以我諗頭先阿阿譚議員嗰個問題咧，就係將來喺無紙化個環境裏邊咧，如果啲投資者係用一個誒非實物嘅方式持有嗰啲股票。
如如果佢直接持有咧，佢就真係一個法定股東，噉佢就會喺股東名冊嗰度咧反映到佢嘅名。但係如果佢透透過券商持持有咧，其實同今日嘅情況一樣，因為佢透過券商持有咧嗰啲股票嘅名咧個持有人法定持有人咧係中央結算代理人，噉佢就唔係一個法定嘅股東嚟，喺股東名冊見唔到佢嘅名。
噉就正正就係頭先阿譚議員嗰個問題，因為佢唔係一個法定股東，所以嗰正常喺誒嗰個股票市場嘅買賣咧，唔需要反映佢背後嗰個投資者嗰個身份喺度啊。係主席，係多謝你解釋嚇。所以咧，我覺得呢一部分咧就係嗰懶人包嘅部分，即係要解到畀個個選項係喺邊度，或者佢點？
點樣去行使呢個選項係重要？即係個法例咧，好似好冷冰冰噉樣嚇。咁但係操作起上嚟嘅時候咧，個嗰個股民如果佢真係想攞翻個legal title，佢想將嗰個法定嗰個所有權都喺自己度咧，即係話頭先你講啦，我連嗰個登記都係喺本人名，我唔想透過銀行或者係券商。
佢揸又經翻原來Custonomy嗰種做法嘅時候咧，佢係要點樣做咁同埋係佢要睇到啲乜嘢？即係如果佢自己查，好似頭先我哋關注噉樣咧，佢喺個register嗰度，佢會睇到啲乜嘢，或者佢會過幾多日佢先睇到嘅噉樣。即係呢啲機制咧，就係對市民嚟講唔係好摸得著啊。譬如。
譬如頭先我哋睇第五條咧，就話其實個issue咧係誒佢都冇限佢其實幾時嘅，總之咧佢reasonably practicable係嘛，即係切實可行，收到足夠嘅資料嘅時候咧，佢就要喺個register嗰度喺個登記冊度咧將呢啲資料抌落去啦。咁咁其實大概係一個乜嘢嘅流程咧？噉我諗呢個。
係值得去普及呢一個嘅嘅知識同埋教育勸嘅。同意，同意啊。O K，咁或者我諗誒，而家仲有誒，嚴江議員作出提問，咁跟住我哋就再繼續去誒，逐條審議係啦。嚴江議員，好多謝主席。誒，噉我睇到咧誒，第六條嘅第二款咧誒，著。
話誒發行人咧，要將嗰個誒新嘅個無紙形式設窗嘅誒持有人嘅登記冊呢個邊間嘅話咧，要發出通知嘅。咁咧發出通知有兩種形式嘅，一種咧以電郵形式咧就email啦嚇，誒第二種咧就誒就寄啦嚇，寄信啦。
計上嘅話咧，誒呢個兩種形式嘅話咧，都係either，就係其中一種都得嘅。誒呢度咧，列明咧第五款咧，列明咧任何人咧，如果違反違反呢一個咧係即縮，即屬於犯罪嚇。咁咧，我想咧。
呢呢一條就係話咧，如果如果要嚴格一啲，應該話可唔可以改成咧係誒快遞嚇？快遞咧，因為如果係揾唔到，你可可以可以打電話啊嘛。如果係打電話，如果呢個人係揾唔到，係退翻咁咧，你誒發現你係知道呢個係揾唔到嘅，每一個咧，either。
And we have we we have updated it or amended it to bring it in line with the USM regime. And that code of conduct will come into effect when the USM regime comes into effect. And there are requirements under that code that deal with the ASR's handling of obligations.
We do require that the share registrars make reasonable attempts, but at the end of the day, there is only so much that they can do, because there are, there are, in a sense, there are different kinds of complaints. There may be complaints from the person who is now residing in the premises where the previous register owner was.
And there may be complaints from the registered holder that you know the address. Although they've updated the address, they haven't received the material. So there are different kinds of scenarios is what I'm trying to get at. And what we have required is basically the share registrar has to do what is reasonable.
誒。
嗯。
或 delivering it personally.
誒，我諗局方聽到呢個呢個意見，睇下有冇任何優化嘅空間啦嚇。噉啊誒，或者我哋繼續逐條審議啦嚇。
咁咧，所以呢個咧，誒當地本地嘅飼料，應該應該話咧，成本都唔高，係嘛？但係咧，呢個咧會誒更加準確一啲嚇。
what would be reasonable in order to make sure they don't create nuisance for say a new occupant of the registered of the address where the registered owner previously was.
過度步驟會有成本 implications for them as well. Ultimately, it's the registered holder's responsibility to update his particulars on the register.
There are some steps that the share registrars take. Whether they include using a courier, I'm I'm not sure, but I would expect that any additional steps or any
邊個時候咧，我寄出嚟㗎嘛？所以啦，如果dispute嗰時咧，僱員應該係更加會更加準確咧，真係係點解決呢個呢個法律上面嘅dispute，因為呢屬於呢個呢個界定係直屬犯罪啊嘛，所以呢個咧應該誒更加嚴緊啊，嚴緊一啲嚇。
It is difficult, really, to be honest, to do anything more than that, because we do need to protect the interests of the registered holder as well. And like I said at the beginning, a lot of these provisions come from the Companies Ordinance. Your suggestion about sending these by courier.
所以，我唔知如果，addresses，to，some，extent，your，your，但係，even，咧，誒，你提供嘅個地址係冇錯嘅。但係咧，我哋咧，如果係平郵嘅話咧，都有機會係係寄失嘅。咁咧，我本人咧都遇到噉嘅情況嘅嚇。有有時候咧寄咧，哇，兩個星期收唔到，咁咧要打電話翻去咧係再寄一次。
或者即係局方可以考慮呢呢一方面嘅建議咯。即係隨著誒科技啊，或者係誒好多呢啲實際嘅一啲情況誒反映過呢啲噉嘅意見誒，睇下喺未來呢度有冇任何空間可以嚇。唔係呢個咧誒，主席呢個咧，因為誒如果違法咧，即係屬於犯罪，所以咧如果有誒。
dispute嗰時咧係好難界定嘅。咁咧，如果誒我我誒我係持有人係嘛，咁咧我虧損你冇冇寄出嚟。噉你你平郵啊，你你有咩你有咩證據話？我已經係寄出嚟㗎啦。你冇啊嘛。如果平郵話咧誒，通常係冇。但係咧，你courier咧係你手度上面有有資料話邊個時候。
嗯，OK，I'm just sorry。同埋誒或者聽聽先嘅陳少紅議員，因為啱啱嗰個條問題已經開始問到嗰個誒下一段㗎啦。咁或者誒陳少紅問問問呢個問題先啦嚇，咁跟住我哋再繼續誒做條審議嚇。啊，主席，我都係想問呢個五嘅括號一二三呢幾個。
部分咧，一定去誒討論一下啦。因為係我擔心就係頭先嗰個誒交流對話入邊咧，誒如果係聽住我哋嘅一問一答嗰啲，可能會有少少誒疑惑或者誤會啊。咁不如索性就都借呢個機會澄清下啦。首先咧，第二步持有人登記冊。
第五條呢一個就係誒要備存持有人登記嘅登記冊。噉我哋頭先都提到啦，一直以嚟我哋關心嘅就係因為個系統係容許實體與電子並存啊嘛。噉就因為有咗電子有個無紙化嘅話，所以呢一個登誒發行人需要備存持有人嘅登記冊。
multiple companies with multiple different state of affairs.
Thank you very much for that question. Again, in fact, we we will be asking.
registered holders to provide their email addresses. Perhaps maybe to step back a bit.
我哋翻翻轉頭講兩樣嘢。第一，誒有咗呢一個無紙化之後，呢個持有人登記冊係點樣用？
before all the holders of each security become USI holders, so we're talking about a situation where you have
所以，what this section is trying to do is sort of put a bottom line requirement, if you like, and say, right, you have to have a ROM. The ROM has to have these minimum requirements set out in there.
聽到即係證監嘅同事嘅即係代表，佢講咗就話其實參考咗其他其他jurisdiction都應該係好有限嘅資料嘅啫，唔會涉及到好好即係誒ID卡啊嗰啲噉樣。嗱呢個明白嘅。
其實都係朝向個電子嗰個，即係或者無紙化嗰部分。咁包括埋個郵遞地址嘅，即係而家譬如我哋而家要申請車牌嘅時候，其實我哋唔需要比較實體地址，我哋可以有個電郵，反而係一個好重要嘅溝通工具。
咁但係我哋如果講係電子化嘅時候，其實我哋真係要邁進電子化嘅咧。而家我哋喺香港特區政府嘅服務啊，已經係朝向電子政府，因此包括埋我哋嘅身份證，包括我哋嘅至方便，包括埋我哋電子車牌。
啲即係第一講咗啲登記冊到最終達到咩嘅目的？第二，如果點解唔考慮埋即係索性一次都係電子化，咪容許誒電子郵件嗰個誒郵箱作為即係地址嘅另類嘅一個登記咧？唔該曬，係田家梅嚇。
就以一個電子嘅形式登記。咁今次寫到係誒五嘅括弧二，涉及到登記嘅內容就係姓名或名稱及地址。噉我頭先啲議員同事都係關心個地址，即係到時要誒郵遞係點樣咧噉樣樣。咁但係成件事。
好簡單啫，就因為我哋今天持實體又好，或者用中央結算，我哋係有即係誒經過代理人去處理一啲實體嘅，其實我哋都有個登記冊嘅。咁但係因為轉咗電子化之後咧，咁當然就有reprint，即係即係類似複製咁上下，就係一個電子化嘅登記冊。咁入邊嘅內容，咁頭先。
噉我就想問就喺呢一方面嘅時候，如果假如佢係提供個地址，就引申咗頭先我啲議員同事們都擔心嘅，就話有個地址錯啊、搬咗啊、點你有冇誒適時更新啊諸如此類噉。咁但係如果電子郵件嗰部分而家都係好普遍㗎啦，咁其實係咪考慮到即係都可以有誒其他嘅一個？
通訊嘅方式咧，包括即係電話或者諸如此類嗰啲噉。個目的嗱，翻翻轉頭就係呢一個誒持有人登記冊，到最終你係點樣用咧？就係要揾嗰個人嘅啊。而且呢個登記冊嘅係一個重要性，唔係好輕率地我求求其擺啲資料喺度咧，因為你係要準確，準確之餘咧又係要要備存。
十年，如果假如你係成個過程中有有啲咩閃失嘅話，其實佢嘅犯罪係可以即係四級罰款等等。咁所以我哋即係不能掉以輕心咧。究竟呢一個登記冊，我哋點樣確保佢嗰個完整性、嘅有效性以及一個合法性啊？咁所以不如索性一次過你。
所以，條文喺《註冊成員》（sorry，《註冊成持有人》）係旨在覆蓋所有指定證券，所以會有一個過程，令所有指定證券的發行商成為參與證券。亦會有個過程。
sorry。
所以，至少 for that。
got a bit lost on the pages.
所以，我們 did 特別地 look at 這 question of email addresses。
所以，which is also why here we talk about.
因為ASR規則也也補充了由一個行為守則，我剛才提到過。
ultimately， if the investor does not provide an email address， there is nothing that the registrar can do。
所以，what we are thinking or what we have in the code now is that we will be requiring the
population of investors, that population of registered holders, there will be an electronic address communication, and that is actually the intention.
所以，的idea是真係要鼓勵和建喺啲誘因，令到投資者用電子嘅方式。
on top of this, there is other regulation that will support this regime, and we will come to it in due course. Especially when we come to the ASR rules.
但 for uncertificated holders, what they can do is that when they set up the USI facility, as part of that process, they will require an email address to be provided.
and when the when the securities in question are in uncertificated form, you must stipulate that clearly. and one reason for that is because the investor will not have a certificate, so the ROM needs to recognise that no certificate has been given to this investor.
registered holders who hold in uncertificated form, they have to provide an email address because the the intention is that everything should be electronic as far as possible. We don't want a situation where registered holders are holding their securities without paper and transferring without paper, but everything else is still in paper.
Where we have the notices being the option there being the notices there being an option there for notices to be in electronic form or paper form, we need to leave the hard copy form there for the investors who have not yet dematerialised, because there has to be protection for them as well. So if they have not
誒。
誒，作出提提問。
電子方式聯絡到你。
比如説證券。
這個我的問題是。
好，哎哎，謝謝主席。
那係 sort of thinking 係 behind that provision.
就是這個持有人登記冊啊，我們現在是要求這個發行人需備存。
能不能就是不一定是發行人？這中間就是這個發行人被妥這個持有人登記冊包不包括髮行人委託？
誒主席一一個跟進問題咧，就係誒理想地啊。頭先我聽所所講就係理想地都希望佢提供個電子嘅誒郵件嘅誒或者郵電子嘅郵件地址。
咁但係喺呢一度係咪可以name and address，即係個姓名及地址或電郵地址咁？咁可以畀到一個即係即係profession，或者畀多多一個選項，佢加落去可以連地址連埋電子郵件嘅地址都寫埋落去。咁呢個係咪可以考慮埋？即係佢可以加多一欄。
Provided an email address, and they have not dematerialised their securities. They should still be entitled to communication, and their communication would have to be by paper. There would be no other option. So that the requirement there is to recognise that you know if you can't do it electronically, you must still do it in paper form.
咁當然就最到你上最理想嘅做法就到最終就全部轉曬，我都唔理你住邊度㗎啦。總之我有個辦法係可以聯絡到你嘅，等於我哋而家啲電子抄牌牛肉乾都已經轉咗，我就要你攞個電子郵件或者誒電子嘅郵件地址，或者係你有一個電。
即係其實佢到最終，你咧想聯絡到嗰個人嘅話咧，其實而家嘅方式已經不限於就係實體寄一封信去畀佢噉。就引申到頭先，我哋啲議員同事都問嘅問題就係：要收唔到啊，點算啊？噉你嗰啲記錄又唔係好誒update，即係唔係好好更新得到啊？噉係因為呢，因為呢個環節已經去到八分鐘啦。咁
我我啱啱，如果我有正確聽誒正確聽到證監會嘅解釋咧，就係當然我哋而家針對淨係呢一部分嘅，就似乎好似比較誒誒，即係要求比較可能未未走到好似啱啱誒多位議員提及嘅，可以更加電子化。不過即係成個監管制度仲有其他。
嘅誒，即係一啲誒方法措施，去去確保有一啲更加便利嘅誒一個處理方式，同埋咧就係誒呢個亦都係一個平衡，因為始終呢係一個有個過渡期，同埋亦都有市場上面存在一啲即係實體紙張嘅，有一啲人即係仲揸住啲實物股票噉，所以變。
變咗誒，另外一方面係要保障嗰啲其他人。佢如果真係提供唔到一個電郵啊，或者未過誒，即係有有呢個能力去去全全部電子化。我諗我聽到嘅就係誒啱啱嗰個回應係噉樣，或者我哋誒去到誒你你你之後再有機會再咁啦，或者我哋畀譚愛行議員誒再。
結算公司。
係證監會啊。
第三方，比如説，這個。
updated and.
發行人可不可以委託？
係，局方有冇啲咩補充下？
那個效率是不是更高呢？
有冇誒跟進？
我我的我的問題就是説，這個。
來準備呢，是不是一定是發行人自己自身來準備？
這個認可的這個登記公司、登記機構來準備這個登記冊呢？
Agent of the issuer would be responsible for maintaining and updating the register.
誒，發行人這是發行人的職責，但是呢，也包括髮行人，比如説我發行人跟第三方跟這個認可的這個登記公司訂了協議，委託他了，也算是發行人履行了這個責任。
Thank you very much for that question. In fact, the register of holders of a listed issuer is always kept by an SFC approved. Currently, they are called approved share registrars, and under the USM regime, they will be kept by the approved securities registrar.
先先補充幾句先嚇。
即係分判你個核准登記公司去做咯，咁所以我哋覺得就係個上市公司一定要保全呢個責任咯嚇。
定附屬法例嗰個權力嘅，咁所以係誒，如果係誒誒係可以修訂嘅，睇下局方有咩補充。多謝主席。睇下政監會啱啱，因為誒一評有幾幾個都，我覺得相信都係幾正面嘅一啲建議嘅，即係可唔可行，或者睇睇下有啲咩回應啊？唔該。
所以我my my takeaway was two points of amendment that was suggested. One was the point about adding or email address, and the other was about considering whether a courier requirement can be incorporated. We will go back and think about this.
噉啊！我哋有啲建議係想去改善嘅話，咁但係通過呢一個只能夠讓政府即係記錄低將來有機會嘅時候一一片去考慮。即係話，主席可能趁呢個機會，我哋想即係我想啊，等大家委員都知道我哋嘅角色與責任喺呢一個嘅流程入邊，我哋係可以做到啲咩嘅地方咧？
那條條文或那條條義務是反映在《股票市場登記條例》的修訂規則中，我們會在討論到這個修訂時再講。但其實的意圖是，這條條目的登記冊必須由ASR維持。當我們説維持，是指。
amend it as as necessary. So, although the obligation on the issuer is the obligation to keep that obligation, cannot be passed because the the register of holders belongs to the issuer. So it has to be the issuer that keeps the register. But the the share registrar or the ASR as an agent
係兩張，即係即係。其實今日大家明白就係上市公司會委任一個誒證券登記公司幫佢去誒保存嗰個股東名冊㗎嘛。咁但係嗰個責任係喺上市公司嗰度嘅。噉我哋好難就係話誒，如果嗰個安排係個誒證。
登記公司佢保存個股東名冊嘅時候發生問題嘅時候咧，我哋就覺得誒呢個情況係個上市公司係冇責任啦。呢個係行唔通，因為上市公司係有個責任去保存個股東名冊，佢可以委託其他人做，但係佢委託完之後嘅責任都喺翻佢自己本身嗰度㗎嘛。咁所以呢條條例咧就即係個責任。
都係放翻喺誒個上市公司，但係頭先我啲同事都講過，就係我哋去監管個核准登證券登記公司嘅時候咧，我哋都有個要求佢保保存個股東名冊。咁所以因為股東名冊嗰樣嘢咁重要咧，我哋即係好難話淨係將個責任咧，就係由個上市公司透過個協議就要個誒可以即。
O.K.下一位誒，陳小紅誒，主席唔好意思啊，我好快有兩樣嘢啫。第一個就係即係誒頭先嘅討論入邊咧，其實我同意啊，主席你所講嗰樣嘢嘅，即係都要保即係維持翻有有紙同無紙化嗰個即係兩者並存嘅一個即係誒系統啦噉樣樣。咁但係呢度我哋講緊就係無紙化啊嘛。
咁所以我建議佢即係陣間翻嚟考慮下，就係係咪可以加一個或電郵地址噉啊？解決咗個問題咧，即係佢可以提供實體地址或電電郵地址。咁但係主席咧連連帶另外一個問題咧，就係誒我哋啲同事都好努力去逐條去審議嘅時候，提出好多嘅問題或者有啲誒想法啊，係。
嗯。
Right, I'm.
I mean, address that.
subclause two。
應該去到第六條啦。Okay, so we'll go to
says that when this clause is triggered, the issuer must give a notice to that person.
O.K.誒咁誒或者而家繼續嗰個逐條審議嘅過程啦嚇，啱啱啲意見希望誒翻去可以認真考慮下嚇，唔該。
regarding the change and and it mentions the the information that that the notice needs to contain is referred to in subclause four.
registered holder is properly notified that the R.O.M. has been amended to reflect his holdings. So this obligation is incorporated for that purpose.
Subclause three talks about the time within which the notice must be given. So if it's electronically, it must be within one business day, and if it is in hard copy form, three business days.
We might consider putting it, making it, elaborating maybe or expanding it further in the code of conduct rather than in legislation. But we we we do do recognise the concern, and so we will try and accommodate that.
Subclause four talks about the information that the notice needs to include, and that includes the confirmation that the change has been effected, which means that it has been recorded on the register of holders, the details of the change, and the date on which the change was effected.
所以 subparagraph one deals with the scope of the application of the provision. So it talks about where the issuer is affecting a change in the register of holders, and the and the change refers to an entry regarding an uncertificated holding of a person or to any other particular of that person.
希望可以優化呢樣嘢，咁但係而家我哋做緊呢一個係一個先定立後審議嘅一個negative rating嚟㗎嘛，咁即係換句説話講，到最後嚟計審完曬啦，我哋只係能夠接受或者唔接受係嘛？即係如果假如有一啲誒優化嘅部分點樣處理呢？呢樣嘢，因為我見到誒就係一句説話。
話叫魔鬼在細節，當條大陣出咗嘅時候，大家好同意拍曬手掌之餘咧，去到而家執行嘅時候，當然政監同埋即係政府都做咗好多諮詢。咁但係去到啲誒執行嘅細節嘅時候，的而且確有啲位可能有有啲棘嘅。噉我哋如果想完善嘅時候，通過我哋呢一個嘅小組委員會，可能。
只能夠即係誒接受或者唔接受到時，如果有啲修改嘅話咧，有有個機制係咪政府可以翻去再修修改咗之後翻翻嚟，又要再另外再重新嘅process咧？呢個係唔理想嘅。咁但係我哋都要考慮到我哋個即係誒個審議嘅效率，因為都有個限期喺度。
我諗喺誒局方嘅層面咧，即係應該有，即係每位誒議員帶帶嚟嘅一啲意見咧。我相信即係誒誒絕有誒國代表緊國界同埋，即係背後一一啲我諗係誒，即係我相信係有廣泛調研過嘅。我相
咁所以即係好多啱啱所講嘅一啲誒提出嚟嗰啲意見咧，即係誒一方面記錄低啦，同埋即係喺技術上係咪誒可行操作到，同埋即係盡最大嘅努力咧去誒去去去實行。咁誒睇下啱啱嗰條問題，仲有冇啲咩誒繼續回應，或者誒法律顧問誒先。
誒多謝主席嘅。誒亦都留意到頭先議員誒問到啦，關於可唔可以誒修訂呢一份附屬法例嘅。咁畀翻誒背景資料啦，根據翻誒第一章誒適宜及通則條例嘅第三十四回二條咧，其實立法會係可以透過誒決議咧，就誒將誒嗰個附屬法例咧作出修訂嘅。咁但係就要需要符合翻定。
條六，所以條六是個條款，基本上要求發行商要給確認給未證實的持有人，每當有修改在持有人名冊中與該人有關。
The rationale for this is that today, when a registered holder has his holdings increased, he will receive a share certificate. So going forward, there will no longer be a share certificate, but there will be an update on the ROM. So the idea here is to make sure that the
啊！
所以。
我是這個意見。
那麼第二個呢，就是這個。
啊！有冇證監會有？
Thank you for that comment and question.
我哋停一停，誒，譚耀恆議員。
第七條還沒寫，還沒説啊，但接下來馬上説，其實也是跟第六條是是內容是一致的。
你第七條查測，查測説要至營業時間查到可以查測，現在都什麼時代了？
誒，這個謝謝，不好意思，剛才因為剛才已經花了比較多的時間講這個無紙化、這個電子方式的問題。
對吧？我我下了班回去晚上不能查冊嗎？不能看看我的持股量是怎麼回事嗎？所以不應該是營業時間啦，啊？
誒，我我我還是想表達下我的觀點。我覺得這個我們這個我們這個審議的是，我們審議的我們審議的是無紙化。
嗯，然後呢？查車不能説你不能少，呃，這個這個每天提供查車的時間不少於兩小時，這都是這都不是無紙化，這都是有紙化。
A point to note is that this this notice would probably would would be sent in a number of scenarios, including for example when there is a transfer, when there is a dematerialisation, when there is a subdivision or consolidation of securities, anything that affects the record in the register of holders of holders.
還是應該朝任何的文件都是無紙化、電子化方向來發展，這是一個與時俱進的問題。我們我們今天在審議這個無紙化，結果還是用還是用記性的方式，要求記性的方式。如果記性沒沒記答，還有還要受處罰，我覺得這是不合時宜的。
The point about still allowing paper, as I mentioned, the reason we need to allow for paper is that we need to allow for the population of registered holders which have not yet dematerialised their securities and have not set up a USI facility, and therefore there is just no other way for the issuer.
係。
readily accessible.
The point about during business hours, the idea is that the register of members is not going to be a register that is sort of available online.
that anybody and everybody can access. That is not the intention. We would perhaps also need to think about whether that poses security risks if that register of members is so.
The two hours per day requirement we think is reasonable. I'm not sure if the member is suggesting that we need it to be longer. If if the if the if the concern is that it needs to be longer, we can definitely go back and revisit that with the share registrars.
saying I want to have extracts of whichever entries they are interested in, and that would be under Rule Eight, and and get that extract from the ASR, and there would be no time limit in terms of a two-hour day or business hour restriction if that option is pursued.
cheaper and more cost-effective to send electronically. So where they have the option to do so, they would naturally do that. But we will go back and look at the ASR code again to make sure it's properly and clearly set out. Your second point was on the inspection.
And its agent the ASR to communicate with them, so I think the paper option needs to be kept, as to whether we should encourage the electronic paper, the electronic option. We do intend to do so. We we will be doing. We are doing so. We will go back and look at the ASR rule.
and we can revisit making this even more clear or expanding on it to make it clear that where the holder is an uncertificated holder, the notice has to be in electronic form. I should mention also that there is a cost element to all this, and so from the issuer's perspective, actually, it is actually
The inspection provisions are cast largely are cast by reference to the existing inspection provisions in the companies ordinance. Given that some of the listed companies are also Hong Kong incorporated companies, we felt it would be better better to sort of align our inspection requirements.
Apart from inspection, there is in Rule Eight a provision for requiring copies of the register. So a person is not necessarily required to go to the share registrar's office to physically inspect. If during business hours, there is the other option of writing into the ASI.
誒，我我諗其實即係誒，對上有幾位誒誒委員同埋，啱啱誒譚議員提出呢個問題，我覺得都係一個誒有少少誒，即係成個嗰個無紙證券制度咧，即係都發發展咗到到今時今日，已經差唔多十幾廿年啦。所以如果我哋真係要，
與時並進嘅話咧，真係有好多我哋誒，可能有少少係超越咗我哋去逐條審議而家入邊嗰啲內容啦。但係的確係我我相信喺誒，無論特區政府又好啦，監管機構啦，真係真係需要即係更加開放嘅態度。好似啱啱所講，我哋唔係話質疑誒嗰個誒，即係入。
係，請嘉妹。
Where there's a possible misentry, if you like.
你係點樣計佢犯法咧？
你哋認為咩叫做無合理辯解咧？嚇！
我諗，第一點要講係。
whenever there is a change in the register of holders.
Okay, thank you for that question. So the first question was about what would constitute a reasonable excuse.
嗰一同一日對住嗰個人，總之你冇做冇冇冇做曬所有嘢，你就罰錢。呢度點樣計算咧？其實？
或者改動啊，或者誒刪改嚇，即係刪減個名。我想請問下喺第六嘅第五咧，嗱呢度就講咧，任何發行人無合理辯解違反第二款就屬犯罪。誒，請問可唔可以誒，或者即係同時可唔可以解釋一下？
連嗰啲條文而家講到第七部分嗰啲誒誒實際嘅內容，但係個方式啊，即係如果你仲係誒，好似啱啱講非營業時間，即係總之你符合到個要求，你可以用一啲更加誒便利、更加即係誒即係善用科技去去去執行嗰啲誒。
誒做到嗰啲相同嘅嘢㗎嘛，咁所以誒呢個我諗誒，即係有少少超越咗，有少少政策上，但係我覺得即係都應該大家提出嚟呢啲噉嘅意見，都係好誒好應該去考慮嘅嚇。或者各方有冇啲咩要回應嚇？主席誒誒同意嘅。誒其實咧誒各位議員剛才講嗰啲都係啲。
好提議咁有一有一點咧，就住呢個誒第第七條咧，我我想提提嘅就係其實佢嗰個誒嗰個主體啊，即係任何人咧，其實未必係嗰個證券嘅持有人嚟嘅，即係所以係一個普通普通市民。噉我哋喺呢度寫嘅咧，即係證監會亦都可以講咧，就係我哋寫嘅都係一啲最基本嘅要求，即係可能誒。
誒誒，當然我哋係喺呢度會有寫就話，營不不少於兩小時嘅時間，亦都係喺一啲嘅即係營營業時間入邊去做呢啲，都係一啲最基本嘅要求。我哋希望有一個最最低水平嘅都提供咗喺度。至於公司點樣去做，或者嗰個登記冊嘅持有人點樣去做，我哋都可以有其他。
嘅手段，即係可能一啲行政嘅措施。誒，我哋就希望佢做嘅嗰個水平一定係高過我哋嘅最低要求。但係即係希望大家都明白咧，就係譬如我哋提出無紙化呢個呢個草案，我哋都好想一步到位，但係事實上我哋亦都係需要啲時間，我哋亦都即係容許平衡噉樣去做，同樣可以有。
誒有紙嘅證券或者一啲無紙嘅證券，咁喺呢度咧查察，亦都可能我哋亦都包含一啲就未必喺即係科技上咁咁先進嘅，可能有啲最最基本嘅，佢可能都用翻一啲誒最傳統嘅方法想去做。我哋所以就寫呢啲基本要求，但係誒隨住時代啦，或者隨住我哋嘅嘅其。
其他措施，我哋都可以誒，有一啲更加更加電子化嘅措施，可以去去擺落去，未必需要喺個法例嗰度寫出嚟。誒，我哋頭先議員講嗰啲，我哋誒同埋證監會都會翻去，即係頭先有講啊，你翻去再睇睇。係。好，多謝主席。誒，下一位誒，江若夫議員。主席，我想問第。
六條嘅嗱，第六條咧，主席就即係其實都相當之重要嘅，因為任何嘅變更通知咧喺理論上咧都佢要發出嗰個誒，即係誒發出嗰個誒更改變更嘅通知。嗱，而變更咧，主席喺第六條裏邊咧係包括可能加你嘅名啊嚇。
咁同埋，另外都係喺第五呢個六嘅五嗰度，我都想問嗱呢度嘅罪行咧，就係話佢冇做第二就屬於犯法啦嚇。噉我想請問你，為於犯法係，因為好多時候誒一個改動一個人可以佢買幾隻誒？我唔知啊，即係佢有幾個交易咧，同一個issuer都好噉。
嗯。
或， we would expect to arise.
OK，下一位誒，簡惠敏語。
It is likely that they would.
但係，如果係佢自己系統上嘅問題，其實呢個係咪應該唔係一個reasonable excuse咧？
to our legislation, so it would be for the court to decide whether the reasonable excuse has been made out.
An appropriate, reasonable excuse. But these are the kind of scenarios that would arise.
for no reason not made an entry, then that offence should rightly kick in. So the reasonable excuse is really where.
If there is that, and that would give them, you know, the the grounds to argue that there's a reasonable excuse. If there actually is no reasonable excuse, if they have just fraudulently or just
They there is a reason why they have not made the entry. Either is because they genuinely have concerns about the transfer. For example, it may also be a systems issue. For example, there might have been a bit of a delay, or there might be
The share registrar and the issuer, being disinterested parties, would basically act on the basis of information they have received. If they are not entering a making an entry which one party to the transfer is requesting.
有 concerns about the transfer itself. It might be that the certificate produced is fraudulent, or they regard the certificate as being fraudulent, or whatever. That my point being is my point being that there would be some reason why the issuer or its agent, the ASR, has not made the entry.
你明唔明我意思？譬如佢一個lot一個batch啊，定係佢總之嗰日啊，即係我呢度覺得係咪好即係好似好唔清晰咁咧嚇？係deletion一個deletion做錯咗就犯法罰錢，因為呢度計fine係計level four啊嘛，主席係咪？噉你係一個deletion冇做到計罰錢咧，定係？
Whenever somebody requests a change in the register of holders, it would be in the context of largely a transfer. Another possibility would be a dematerialisation, but dematerialisation is unlikely to affect their actual holding. So transfer would be the most likely scenario where there's possible dispute, or.
some some hiccup somewhere and so they haven't made the entry yet but they are acknowledging it and they're making taking steps or maybe there's been some delay as a result but they have some reasonable excuse as a I mean obviously they have to demonstrate that the system issue was a reasonable issue to have arisen and which gives them a
有冇答到你問題？主席，我個追問啫。嗱，如果頭先講到system system嘅問題嚇，system嘅問題，咁如果個system嘅問題係自己issue，佢個system問題係佢自己可以係改變得到或者係提升得到，理論上係咪唔應該係一個reasonable excuse？嗱，如果你話停電，主席，我好明。
I agree. If it is something out of the issuer's control, then it would it would be a reasonable excuse, like a breakdown, a shutdown in electricity. But if it is something that's within its control, then it wouldn't be. But this is something that the court would decide, right? I mean, a lot of the provisions have this kind of a qualification. This is not unique.
has no email address for this person.
The issuer is now a participating issuer.
Securities, but has not yet set up a USI. So, for example, he holds shares in Paperform.
provisional system member， and the difference between them is that the provisional system member has actually not completed the process of setting up the USI facility.
嘅持有人嚇，我哋我想強調就係呢一條咧，就特別係針對嗰個無紙嗰啲嘅持有人㗎嘛嚇，咁所以我唔係好理解到嚇，頭先即係證監會答啊陳議員嘅時候咧，就話嗰第二條嚇，啊即係喺。
係，謝謝你。Actually，thank you very much for that question. It's actually a very good question. The reason there is a paper option is because uncertificated holdings can be held by two types of persons. One is a system member, and one is a
其實都係係嗰個無止嘅，已經具備呢啲條件嘅朋友嚇，嗰啲嘅股民佢先會開個USI噉樣去去有個噉嘅賬户同個誒ASO，即係嗰啲approved securities registrar㗎啦，係咪？咁所以對佢哋嚟講。
誒唔該，主席誒嗱，因為我哋咧就係逐條逐條咁審啦，所以當我哋頭先討論第五條嘅時候咧，就提議下有同事就提議，即係話有電郵地址噉樣。咁但係我哋而家審到呢個第六條嘅時候咧，就見到咧，如果喺有一啲變更嘅情況咧，嗰個發行人點樣通知翻呢啲無紙化？
啊！呢個六嘅括弧二嗰度嚇，就提到可以仲畀個發行人有兩種方式去選擇嘅時候咧，當時答就話有一啲咧就仲係有紙化嘅持有人，所以留翻個寄信嘅選項畀佢。噉我覺得呢一個嘅答法係同呢一條唔係即係喺翻呢一條嗰個情景底下。
嚇，因呢一條其實就係集中講無紙化嘅持有人咧點樣收到通知嚇。咁會唔會即係既然整合咗我哋頭先第五、第六條嘅討論，包括吳議員頭先提到話，即係可唔可以擺翻個電郵地址啊？江議員都有提到，即係幾位都話要應該跟你呢個即係與時並進，而且咧你入得個U.S.I.嚇，其
誒就佢哋唔係啲有紙化嘅持有人，我想講，即係呢個第六條係咁點解仲要畀一個選擇畀嗰個發行人咧？咁好似令到個發行人咧就咁又得咁又得噉樣樣嚇噉就頭先有阿嚴議員所講嘅，會唔會噉樣佢選擇咗紙本嘅時候咧？噉我收唔到咁又點咧？個
責任噉樣嚇，即係會唔會喺無紙化嘅情景咧？你不如就索性就係用電郵，然後就喺嗰個對佢哋而言個register咧，就可以有個電郵作埋一個通知嘅途徑嚟嘅嚇，就唔好畀個選項個個持有人好冇咧？除非咧，就係呢一個選項咧。
係畀嗰個USI holder嘅，即係個USI holder話：我仍然中意紙，噉就係啦。但係你而家個選項係畀個發行人㗎嘛？噉我唔知你用咗咩嘢嘅選項嘅時候咧，你個我我冇辦法啦。即係話我作為個無紙化嘅持有人咧，好似由得你選擇用咩方式通知咗我噉樣樣嚇。即係主席啊，我希
噉樣嚇，咁為咗帶翻去睇睇嚇。好嘅，好。
In code or guidelines, you know, we're happy to consider that.
冇嗰個誒，即係爭議喺嗰度嚇，即係可以分開少少。即係既然操作上原來係噉嘅，都等大家有個明確性嚇。
The increased use of electronic rather than paper—it's in everybody's interest to do that. But there may be a small population of people or investors who still want to get their communications in paper form for whatever reason.
所以，although the provision is limited to securities that are held in uncertificated form, there is still a possibility that you have a person whose email address is not with the issuer.
局方或者係證監會嗰度有冇任何再收窄多少少嗰個空間，令到即係你畀大家個選擇更加電子化？係啊，We can definitely go back and think about it. Um, what we the reason we didn't make the distinction um is because
We wanted to leave the option to the investor, and through incentives and disincentives, sort of drive the investor towards going for an electronic option. I think we are more than happy to, you know, in fact everybody wants.
and we didn't want to sort of you know deny them that option, but it would not be an easy option. I mean, easy in the sense that they would they would need to wait longer. For example, they would take three days and they would probably be a cost attached to it. So, like you say, like you will see, there's nothing here that talks about.
希望我我其實我哋最初參與呢個小組委員會咧，其實唔預計係要討論咁耐嘅嚇，即係好誠實咁講嚇。不過我諗呢一個都重要嘅嚇，因為我哋二一年嗰個法例做咗咧，而家就係落實嗰啲操作嘅規則啊嘛。咁所以我希望可以即係互動嘅時間，都希望即係局方可以即係open mind。
噉佢即係誒誒開放啲嘅態度，因為我哋呢度都係證券界嘅朋友，即係都知道嗰個操作上咧都反映業界嗰個個情況嚇。我唔明白你呢度留呢個選項畀嗰個發行人嘅時候咧，係咪對嗰個持有人嚟講對佢係最好嘅誒嘅嘅處理嘅方法嚇？唔該你。
所以，他們實際上 may not have given an email address to the issuer that the issuer can use. So, when we spoke last week about the definitions, I don't know if you remember, we talked about system member and provisional system member. So, the provisional system member is someone who receives uncertificated holdings, uncertificated securities.
他 is it is distributing bonus shares. The bonus shares can only be in uncertificated form, so they will be given to him in uncertificated form. But he has not set up a USI facility, so a temporary or provisional facility is set up for him, and his holdings are still uncertificated. But the issue is still
係嗱，主席誒，多謝即係局方再喺度即係去去解釋翻個操作上面嚇。咁但係喺個喺個法例即係喺個規則上面咧，我哋唔知道佢個實操嘅情況嚇。咁如果係噉嘅時間咧，你係咪應該話，如果佢嗰個U.S.I嘅嘅facility佢相關嘅設施已經開咗？
咧就用呢一個只係用電郵嘅方式。如果佢未開咧，先至留翻嗰個paper form嗰個即係個紙本嘅方式嚇。咁大家其實睇個規則嘅時候咧，亦都清楚。如果我未成功開到嗰個U.S.I.F.S.L.A字嘅嘅話咧，我就我就assure即係我自
幾多個確切性咧？就係我會用紙收到為準㗎啦，因為我我先知道會唔會係轉讓咗啊，或者你畀啲bonus share我啊嘅時候咧，我就唔會諗第二種方式啦。但係如果我已經係有個U.S.I.facilities咧，噉我就要明白咧，我只會從電子嘅方式嚟到去收到去確認我嗰。
嗯。
所以。
Subclause four deals with the.
《The Companies Ordinance》、《Subsidiary Legislation》 on inspection。
Then subclause five deals with contravention being an offence.
Clause seven is the inspection of the register.
誒，我諗繼續逐逐條審議啊，去到第七啦，我諗你可以繼續誒，證監會嚇。
So sub clause two deals with the the timing. So the inspection must be during business hours.
and there may also be reasonable restrictions, but whatever restrictions there are, the register must be open for at least two hours a day.
This has been cast by reference to Section 631 of the Companies Ordinance, which also deals with inspections of registers of holders, as well as
Subclause three clarifies that the scope, if you like, the limitations on inspection. So if the register is closed, then then it it wouldn't be made available for inspection.
provisions of the subsidiary legislation on inspection under the companies ordinance. So subclause one deals with the person's right to inspect. The right is limited to persons who are registered holders. It is not
And if public inspection is permitted under the underlying law for the relevant securities, that's fine. If it's not, that's also fine. We didn't want to dictate it one way or the other, but we did want to make it clear that at least the registered holder should have the the right to inspect.
係誒，郭玉寬誒，主席好快啫。我想請問一下，咁即係話喺七一咧，即係呢一度係一個person，即係任何人啦。咁呢個係一定係包埋，譬如如果有嗰啲人係死咗嘅，係包埋佢嗰啲intended executor或者嗰啲lawyer，啱唔啱咧？
個無紙嘅股權嘅持有嘅狀況啦，噉樣嚇。即我諗歸根到底都係盡盡量電子化咯。即因為如果你畀大家太多選擇，咁即即大家就會選擇一啲即坦白講唔係好無紙證券嘅一個制度，亦都唔係即除咗個科技嘅發展咯。
責任完成咗未啊？因為呢度都有法律後果。除咗個電子化之外咧，就仲要對個issuer嚟講，同埋對嗰個holder嚟講咧，大家都有個確切性。啊，如果我係已經有個USF facilities咧，我就唔唔會拗你寄咗畀我未。個issuer亦都唔可以拗話，我用紙畀咗你啦，你收唔到啦，噉就。
This having to be free, so the share registrars can easily through cost incentives, sort of persuade investors towards electronic options. But we are also very happy to sort of limit the options altogether if that is the preference. We can do that in the legislation itself. We can do that.
啊！嗱，主席就住呢個回應咧，我諗要留意嘅咧就係一呢個咧係有寫咗係免費嘅，即係無論你用咩方式咧，嗰個發行人都要免費提供啦。第二咧就話呢個選項咧唔係喺嗰個投資者度，係一個發行人度，即係而家個草擬方式咧係個選項畀發行人嘅，就唔係畀投資者。
即係如果個選項認為係畀翻個投資者係可以嘅話咧，咁都可以咁改嘅啊。咁等有啲投資者係真係喜歡，就算佢用咗無紙化嘅證券，但係佢嘅證券有咩變動咧，佢都係中意用紙嘅話咧，你個選項就畀佢啦。咁但係而家你個草案個選項唔係畀佢，係個發行人自己選擇。
Extended beyond registered holders. Having said that, many registers, especially company registers under company legislation, are open to public inspection. We have not included that element in this legislation because we didn't feel it was necessary for the purposes of USM.
誒。
證監會。
提供給他。
係，證監會。
If they are.
好闊嘅嚇，係咪可以包埋呢啲人嘅？
可以誒加加快呢？能不能有這種選擇呢？啊，謝謝。
好誒，check咗之後，我諗再誒通知我哋下一位係譚望衡議員。
Actually, as far as an existing registered holder is concerned.
誒，謝謝主席，謝謝主席。就第七條咧，還是我剛才誒提到過，就是説，除了營業時間。
日，就是這個持有人呢提出申請以後啊，交了錢以後啊，要十個營業日才。
Thank you for those questions. So, on the question about whether the investor why the investor can't inspect at any time.
My take is that it should, because the executor or personal representative steps into the shoes of the member. But if you will permit me, I will go back and check that to be sure. Thank you.
making of copies during an during an inspection, so it the idea is that when a person when a registered holder comes to inspect the register, they must be able to make copies, but there is no obligation for the issuer to assist them in doing so. This clause is similar to provision in the companies registry. I'm sorry.
誒，發行人能不能就是在在線上是上載了這個名冊，然後呢，這個持有人他輸入他的密碼，是可以去查的，這樣就可以大大的便利這個持有人在任何的時間有需要的時候去查他這個誒所需的資料，那。
這是一個，第二呢，就是下面那個還沒還沒説啊，第八條啊，我呃，不好意思，我我也説一下，就是第八條這個，就是説這個要求。我先講埋第八條，我哋去到第八條。我我因為我我我等你。哦，OK，好好，OK OK，等等。就是第八條，就是十個工作十個營業日。
呃，your question。
所以，我 think，我唔 know if that would address。
噉啊誒，即係跳去前邊少少，因為啱啱誒譚議員都有問到第八條喎，睇有冇啲簡單嘅回應。
the ROM, if you see what I mean, but of course it's not exactly the same as checking the ROM. I accept that, but I'm what I'm trying to say is that it.
holders and checking your own portfolio, but because your question, as I understood it, was that
registered holders where they they provide an online facility where the registered holder can view their own holdings.
這樣的話，投資人可以這個，呃，不限定他只是在營業時間，或者是兩，呃，呃，兩個小時這樣的，呃，數字上的規定。
If there is an urgency for that individual to check his holdings, to view his holdings outside of office hours, he will actually have a platform to do that.
是，就是説，我們還是鼓勵有條件的這個上市公司會提供這個通過電子化、線上的方式上載這個名冊。
即係話十日啊，因為十日嗰個引時太長，可能要有啲打官司啊，或者有啲緊急嘅情況，睇下可唔可以快趣誒加快誒去去批核呢啲噉嘅情況啊。
the two the two hours per day and business hours may not be convenient for everyone, and you are suggesting to therefore put the entire register of holders online. So rather than
holding an uncertificated holding， they will actually have full time access to their portfolio。 in fact， many share registrars even today they have the service for
這個這個持有人，他要他要這個，其實有時候可能是法律上的需要、打官司的需要或者是什麼提供證明的需要，他很急的，那一定要等十個營業天以後才能收到。他有沒有可能，比如説你們提供一個更多的選擇，他可以加快呢、加急呢？呃，多付費就？
即係我諗個意思就係話，如果係誒持持有人本身佢有好多嗰個啲啲誒個處提供服務，佢哋自己本身都有啲平台噉，即係基本上實時都係非辦公時間，佢哋都可以睇到嘅。誒，我諗呢，我我理解啊，即係誒，就係如果喺呢條。
法例就係講緊有一啲可能非持股人或者有啲其他嘅原因，佢要去再查下呢啲噉嘅資料咧，就誒喺呢啲咁情況底下就係一個誒，即係辦公時時間。我嘅理解係咪正確咧？So I guess there's maybe a slight difference between inspecting the RAM, inspecting the register.
rather than putting the entire register of holders online, another option would be for the investor who, if assuming he is a holder of uncertificated securities, because he would have online access via his USI facility to view his portfolio at any time. So that would go to some way to checking.
嗯。
and so.
listed overseas. sorry
go beyond what was necessary for U.S.M.
Yeah, I'm sure Sherajustras would offer services for for speedier services. I think.
the shareholder who no longer has a certificate should be able to inspect the register of holders if it wishes to.
當我們設計這，當我們 casting 這些 provisions， our focus on was on what is absolutely necessary， and we felt that at a minimum
Incorporated overseas, so we didn't want our legislation to go beyond what is necessary for USM.
the sorry the second question was about balancing the right of public access and the registered holder, so.
Thank you for the question, Chairman. So the two-hour requirement really is just comes from this company's ordinance. Because, like I said at the outset, we have drawn reference to the company registry ordinance. We did not want to.
呢度有講到嗰個誒誒，我諗最最主要呢兩方面先咧，想聽下嗰個誒證監會有啲咩回應，關於嗰個兩個鐘頭同埋即係誒點樣去平衡嗰個發行人同埋即係要查核資料嘅人嘅嗰啲誒權益噉樣嚇。
I mean, one option is for the legislation to set out all of this. What we the approach we're taking is that this is a baseline service level that we expect. So if the share registrar wants to offer more expedited services for a higher fee, it's entirely open to them to do so.
誒，我諗係啦，睇下仲有冇誒第二部分嘅補充。即係我諗啱啱證監會嘅回應就應該講就話唔係話一定，即係基本上誒有好多啲持股人咧，佢哋係有其他方式，即係都可以喺線上度睇到一啲非辦公時間睇到啲資料。不過啱啱仲有第第八條。
即係實際操作上，應該就係呢個呢個法律就係畀咗個最低門檻，但係應該有一啲加快嘅方式去誒攞到啲有關資料㗎啦。嚇誒，跟住到我都想再出一個提問喺第七條呢度咧。誒，因為誒都同譚議員啱啱問嘅關注點有相類似。
嘅，因為呢度即係有提及到就係嗰個誒查閲持股人登記冊誒內嘅記項嗰度咧，佢誒即係任何人，即係如果佢提出呢個要求，呢度又講到話係誒免費嘅嚇，所以呢度第一講免費啦，第二就係話誒即係兩個鐘頭，我都想了解下，因為你要平衡誒。
誒可能發行人自己本身誒，即係一啲係咪合理嘅要求啊，或者係誒，即係要誒用好多資源去滿足到誒一啲人嚟做一啲查，但係同時間咧，亦都誒係咪兩個鐘頭太長太短？你哋係點樣去釐定呢個兩個小時咧？誒，同埋呢？
As far as we're aware, for shares, the companies, at least in the case of Hong Kong companies, the register of members is open for public inspection. For OFCs also, it's open for public inspection. We're not sure whether for all of the securities listed on the SEHK, there are similar provisions, especially those.
係。
誒。
但。
nor do the provisions on copy.
differ from the company law provisions, so the company law.
好，或者我哋繼續逐條審議，可以誒，繼續。
係七仲有補充，如果第七條冇補充，就可以去到誒第八㗎啦嚇。
offences for inspection do not have a daily fine and.
Subclause one confirms the right to get a copy on request and payment.
We didn't see a need to expand that to go beyond the registered holder from from the for the purposes of the U.S.M. regime.
Thank you for that question. So again, it was by reference to the company company ordinance provisions. We we didn't see any need to.
So clause eight is about requesting copies of the entries of the register of holders. So this is again cast by reference to the co equivalent provisions.
我哋都一定係背後有原則嘅，我相信。一間譬如喺某一啲嘅section嘅時候，我指出其實你係好難有daily fine嘅，好難去到釐定daily fine。咁或者呢個，我想make個note啫嚇，唔該。
請問一下，啊，不如第七我都明嘅，第七佢冇一個即係特別嘅時限嘅嚇，但係譬如第八咧嚟緊，我哋一陣間睇咧就會有。我想請問一下，冇有時有daily fine，有時冇daily fine，其實嗰個原則係咩咧？請問？
好，嗯，係一位誒，江玉寬議員。誒，主席，我想請問一下咧，嗱喺條條例裏邊咧，好多嘅罰則咧都係有講到，就係話四級罰款啦，即係一個罰款啦，加埋一個daily fine噉。嗱，其實去到第七、第八條咧，我就見咗冇咗daily fine嘅嚇。噉啊，我想。
主席，我呢度想make個note啫，我唔係要改嚇，放心。不過即係話我自己覺得呢樣嘢就唔係好理想，一陣間嚟緊有幾條section我都會有啲問題，就係話當我哋要每日罰款同埋唔需要每日罰款嘅時候咧，其實我自己覺得雖然我哋我知道係根據公司法咧，好似頭先阿Miss Pocatam噉樣講，但係呢個我。
clarifies that.
request。
and。
needs to have sufficient particulars.
它可以包括歷史記錄的條目。
subclause two.
And subclause four makes it an offence to breach this provision.
subclause，sorry，I beg your pardon。
提供The copy within ten business days and upon payment of the specified fee.
所以，的copies must relate to an entry made in relation to that person.
Sub sub clause three deals with the time and the payment of a fee, so it talks about the issuer having to.
Subclause five definition provisions. So basically, just defines what is meant by electronic form, and we do that by reference to the ETO.
Again, we have the option to do it in hard copy or in electronic copy, per the request of the person in question.
and of course because there is a there is the ability for the issuer to destroy after ten years, so the obligation to request for copies should not cover records that have been lawfully destroyed.
defines hard copy to mean paper, and it expands on what is the specified fee. That the rates we have put in here are again by reference to the company ordinance rates.
Basically, the idea is that there must be sufficient particulars provided to the issuer in order to make the copy available. So, if the person requesting the copy has not provided sufficient particulars, the issuer cannot then discharge its obligation. And so, sub clause two is really just to clarify that the.
跟。
係。
係證監會。
會問下明唔明我意思？即係呢一度淨係擺喺第八條。
根本形式，噉我哋點解一定係喺呢一條嗰度先至去定義佢咧？唔該。
即係中文就係管限條文噉樣咯。唔該曬嚇，唔該。
係點解冇？Yeah, there is. Thank you for that question. There is a definition. I'm just trying to dig it out.
或者先生係咪有有啲補充嚇？誒都係主席咁誒，回應簡議員嘅問題，嗰個指明費用咧喺呢度嘅定義係淨係適用於第八條嘅係。
點解？即係因為成分其實成個成個L N十五都會有機會出現到Electronic Form電子形式、Hard Copy印本形式嘅。點解特別要喺第八條先定義佢咧？係我諗翻顧問有啲補充嚇。
boy嗰度咧，英文咧就有一個叫governing provisions，想請問呢個有冇definition咧？我睇過company ordinance同埋睇過SFC ordinance嗰個誒，即係securities and future ordinance都冇嘅。請問呢個係點解咧？唔該。
誒，我哋而家誒有有提問，就係江玉虎議員。主席係，我想請誒，可能即係誒阿Miss McAdam翻去都睇一睇阿Person喺呢一度第八條係咪同樣都會include埋嗰個intended administrator同埋佢嘅legal representative咧？第二咧，我就想問咧，主席喺二。
或者係誒資生係係咪有有有嘅係誒？多謝主席係誒喺翻個U.S.M. rules本身第二條嗰度係定義咗個加分。請問你講大聲啲得唔得？喺邊度咧？啫哦，sorry，係喺翻我哋而家審議緊嗰條嘅U.S.M. rules裏面第二條。
答咗你問題啦，係咪啊？係。O.K. 好。誒，下一位係簡惠敏議員。好。誒，主席。誒，我想請教就係呢一度咧，喺第五款嗰度嚇，就定義咗電子形式誒同埋印本形式同埋咧指明費用啦嚇。咁呢一度咧係淨係限於呢個第八條定。
定係定係點樣咧？即係呢個index rule呢個中文就係在本條中，淨係喺第八條嗰度啊？定係點樣嚇？因為其他地方，譬如我哋頭先討論到第六條嘅時候咧，都有講到話，如果嗰個變更嗰個名冊嘅時候咧，都可以用電子形式同埋一。
唔係，我仲有嚇呢個指明費用適用於第八條啦。咁但係咧就係電子形式同埋印本形式咧，唔係淨係出現喺第八條㗎嘛。我諗主席明我意思嚇，即係譬如前面第六條都有講到點樣發通知嘅時候咧，我哋都有用到e-ronic form同埋hard copy form呢啲字眼嘅。咁但喺第六條嘅時候，究竟咁又？
點解咧？係嘛？即係嗰個定義係咩意思咧？點會喺呢個淨係第八條先至需要定義佢咧？還是係講我成個part啊？係咪本部都係適用咧？即係成個part two都適用啊？定係索性係成個我哋呢度L.N.十五整個U.S.M.嘅規則都適用咧？唔知法律？
嗯。
所以。
The limit on the closure period for the register of members.
會當局去考慮有冇呢個需要係多謝主席。好。
因為其他部分都有用到呢呢個詞嚇，呢個我認為就應該擺翻去啊廣泛啲去適用，唔好淨係擺擺喺第八條啦，嚇唔該。
好，嗯，可以繼續誒介紹逐條審議嘅嚇部分。Okay, so the next one is clause nine, which is
normally the companies normally companies legislation allows for the closure of a register of members and there is a limit of in many cases about 30 days per year.
所以， sub clause one talks about the scope of the application of this rule. So it applies to the register of holders of any whenever the register of holders can be closed.
所以我們有包括這條款，主要目的就是限制關閉到不超過兩天，或者如果要長的話，那就要是一個期間，期間交易是暫停。
under the applicable law or their own governing provisions, and secondly, the securities are participating securities. So we're talking here not about, we're talking here only about securities that have become USM enabled.
We have we wanted to restrict that right a bit more in the USM environment. The reason is that if we close the ROM for too long a period, it will prejudice investors who hold securities in their own name outside of SECAS.
出現嘅，所以嗰個位置係咪可以放翻在喺上誒上面係啦，即係唔可以話因為原來有一條有噉，我照搬咗佢過嚟。咁但係其實呢兩個詞喺整個部分或者係整個L N十五咧都有出現嘅話咧，即係或者你睇下點樣處理啦，即係從起草嘅角度嚇。唔該。好。
誒多謝議員嘅提問嘅。咁如果睇翻現時嘅草案方式咧，佢淨係喺誒第誒第八條嘅括五嗰度咧有相關嘅定義。咁所以咧呢一個電子形式嘅定義，淨係會適用於係第八條嘅啫。咁至於使唔使將一個誒統稱嘅定義咧擺喺撇擺翻喺誒第二條嗰度，就應該係政府。
嘅提問或者解釋翻個緣由咧，因為誒呢兩個定義咧，好好似頭先誒Miss McCallum所講咧，我哋係參即係成個第八條係參照公司條例底下嘅附屬法例第六二二I章入面第十一條，裡面佢有定義到即係電子形式同埋印本形式嗰個。
個定義，所以就就住第八條咧，我哋都係相應咧，係誒，即係加入翻嗰個兩個定義嘅。咁至於簡言個問題話，咁但係其他條文入面都有同樣嘅提述喎。咁呢個定義係咪應該適用於嗰啲其他條文嘅提述咧？噉我諗呢個係即係都可以，我哋去考慮係咪？
食用，如果係嘅話，都即係可以考慮係咪需要，即係整即係將呢啲定義擺喺整條食用嘅噉。但係即係我諗呢個，我哋要翻去即係同即係我哋即係內部去考即係參參考一下先係。係我諗誒，局方去考慮下誒，將呢樣嘢，因為即係喺個文件其他地方都會有。
啊，highly。
obligation.
maybe I pause there to see if there's any questions on that clause.
The issue of certificates and the issue and the use of title instruments.
The reason is because the provisions in the legislation which prohibit
Subclause three talks about the commission's ability to exempt this.
power, but because it's a new area, we wanted to leave that flexibility open in case it did become necessary.
所以， any person can apply to the court for rectification if they feel that their name is without sufficient cause entered or omitted.
Subclause two talks about the actual restrictions. So it says that it cannot be more than two consecutive days or any longer period during which trading is suspended.
Unexpected and exceptional situation, which in fact we cannot even imagine today that what that situation might be. But we wanted to leave that flexibility just in case it became necessary.
So, subclause through subclause three goes on to expand on the power of exemption to talk about you know imposing conditions, amending and revoking the the exemption and the conditions.
但the pre prerequisites for any such exemption would be that none of the securities are actually in uncertificated form, which is probably quite difficult to be the case. but
OK，可以繼續嚇。Right， then I move on to clause 10. Clause 10 is again modelled on a CO equivalent provision， which is the court's right to rectify the register.
We have included this exemption power really just for flexibility. We do not actually envisage. We don't do not actually have a specific scenario in mind where we might exercise this.
I think that would have to be because if if any of the securities were in uncertificated form, it would be difficult to meet criteria two, which is prejudicing investors. So for that reason, we have put both those criteria. We can come to how this can work if it becomes absolutely necessary.
There is an exemption power for that as well, and so in the very highly unlikely and extreme scenario where we do need to allow for a book closure for for some reason, we could reverse what has happened. But I have to emphasise that number one, this is not what we are encouraging. It is.
所以。
assistants.
as having ceased to be a member.
and the third party is the issuer.
subclause four deals with.
Subclause five talks about.
what the court needs to consider when determining an application.
and it can also generally decide any question necessary or expedient for the rectification.
maybe somebody who feels that their their hold that the register should reflect their holding but it doesn't.
或如果有任何 delay in entering their name in the register or or remove sorry removing the their name as
and also any record which they feel without sufficient cause has been entered or omitted regarding the number of units held and the number that are in uncertificated form.
sorry not what the court needs to but what they can decide so they can it clarifies that the court can decide any question relating to the title of any person who is a party to the application.
the extent to which this rule applies, it just clarifies that this rule applies only to the extent that the application is not prohibited, or in conflict, or inconsistent with any other laws.
who may want some rectification, it this this is possible because it might be that an entry has been made, but it cannot be corrected without the court's
Subclause three deals with the powers of the court, so the court can, on such an application, refuse the application, or make an order to rectify the register, or make an order to on the on the issuer to pay damages.
所以，the person who may exercise this power are basically persons who are aggrieved. So this may or may not be a registered holder. So a registered holder may obviously have concerns that their entries are not accurate, that it doesn't accurately reflect their holding. An aggrieved person
啲。
那會 be the logic.
mental health.
所以，如果，如果。
The provisions that are set out there by way of example are provisions.
A possible transfer would be an obvious one. You also asked about the mental persons.
yeah，所以第二個問題就係關於誰是同意的人，所以一一個可能性會係一個轉學。
who have guardians appointed. I think there is separate legislation that deals with that. We have, I believe, a.
ordenance, ordinance, something, yeah. So I think separate legislation deals with the rights of the guardians to step into the shoes of
O.K.，即係主席，即係話，如果錯名咧，就淨係share register都可以改㗎啦，就唔需要去到法庭。If it's an error, sorry, it's an error.誒，第二個問題咧，請問係。
但 if the share registrar or the issuer is not, it does not agree that it is simply a correction, then it would, then you would be able to say that the name of the person is without sufficient cause omitted.
嚇，譬如個名唔對啦，呢個就只係話，啊，譬如係omitted啦，嚇，噉係咪都會包埋咧？即係話that the name is without sufficient cause entered in，咁如果錯嘅名係咪都可以申請ratify嘅？
一啲mental health啊嘅order裏邊，佢嘅guardian或者係一啲executor包唔包嘅咧？嗯，係張家梅。Yeah, so um, thank you for the question. So the first question is about what if the name is not um correct? I think you were saying.
I think there is a distinction between correction and rectification. So if it is actually an error, it is open to the share registrar to make the correction. So if it is satisfied that the name is incorrect, misspelled or whatever, then that that's fine.
of wrong rectification that already exist in our legislation, so that is just there for reference。嗯誒，江玉歡議員有主席，我有好快嘅問題啫。我想請問一下喺十嘅一咧誒，如果包唔包括就係話啲人，譬如如果個名啊個名唔對咧？
第二或者需唔需要用呢個程序？可能原來喺company solen水邊已經有另外一個更簡單嘅程序，噉啊更好啦，係咪？第二嘅A咧，我就想請問一下受屈嘅人，即係咩人可以申請咧？其中一個就係任何感到受屈嘅人。咁呢個任何感到受屈嘅人包唔包括譬如話under？
誒減為乜嘢？
the the person involved.
個責任亦都係太大啦嚇，噉樣所以我哋一陣即係稍後會審議到相關嘅規定，我哋再睇睇，唔該。
The ASR's role, vis-à-vis the register, is really as agent of the issuer. So if there is a
佢等於個transferer或者個holder咧，可唔可以咁講？Thank you for the question. Yes, I think that would be correct. That would be my understanding. Thank you.
An award ordered against the issuer, and it's actually due to some default of the ASR, then it would be a matter for the issuer to follow up on with the ASR.
I think the point to emphasise in this context is that the ASR is always acting as an agent. The ASR is not acting as a principal at any point in performing its roles in vis-à-vis the register of holders.
The register of holders belongs to the issuer because the the register reflects holders of the issuer, so the register of holders belongs to the the issuer. the the obligations are therefore also imposed on the issuer.
我明主席，咁即係唔緊要嗰個。當然有嗰個啊誒，ordinance。噉我即係make sure咧，其實即係如果假設嗰個人係有一個即係誒，佢有一個誒order嘅，佢係一個guardian嚟㗎啦。咁理論上佢step into the shoes嘅時候，咁應該就係話佢應該係咪都係會等於嗰個係受屈嘅，因為
主席，我想問三B嘅，嗯，因為三B咧就講個法庭嚇可以做啲咩命令嘅嚇。咁呢度咧就包括咧就係話可以更正啦，咁同埋咧就係命令嗰個發行人就任何感到受屈嘅一方所蒙受嘅損失咧嚟到去畀嗰個賠償。
嘅噉，我想問就係點解淨係個發行人咧，會唔會即係因為可能個做錯嘅係個A.S.O.嚇，就可能係個register噉，即係呢個同阿譚議員嘅早前問嘅問題一樣嘅。咁個法例就好似即係整體咧，包括備存個誒股東名冊啦嚇，即係。
register holders啊，同埋係要記入嗰啲嘅資料啦，同埋呢度咧，即係出咗咩問題咧，都係淨係誒個法庭命令咧，就好似係罰個發行人。會唔會即係係包括埋A.S.O.，定係咧係會你要留翻個issue同個A.S.O.自己之後？
後再去爭拗啦，即係如果個issue啊畀法庭罰咗，咁個issue啊再去誒向嗰個誒register咧嚟到去追討，即係咁個理念係點樣？唔該，係專家冇錯。Thank you for that question. So that's correct. So it would be a matter for the share registrar to follow for the issue to follow up with the share registrar.
係，主席嗱，噉我明白嘅嚇，因為即係誒個issue先就係嗰個主持人啦，佢個principal啦噉樣嚇。咁但係我哋稍後都會審議同A S O有關嗰啲嘅規則嚇。噉我都要希望即係攞到個平衡啦。即係我哋喺規管上面咧對個A S O都要要要合適嘅規管。如果唔係咧，即係對個發行人。
O.K.噉我哋而家接近十一點啦，咁或者可以誒十第十一條講埋，因為淨係得誒兩兩部分嘅。噉我哋就差唔多今日誒到到呢度，或者十一可以講埋先。O.K. Thank you, Mr. Chairman. So, Rule Eleven talks about the effect of entries on the register of mem on the register of
holders， and essentially it basically says that if the if there is an entry in the register， it is in the absence of evidence to the contrary， it's proof of the matter is entered。 so this is similar to what is already in the company's ordinance。 sub sub rule two talks about the uncertificated holdings and it
誒，如果冇其他事項咧，就宣佈會議結束。多謝各位。
嗯，議程第二係其他事項，睇下有冇其他事項。
分至到六時三十分，同埋咧係三月誒二十五日誒星期二下午誒二時至到四時嘅。
它反映，那一紀錄，指示任何數量的單位在 uncertificated form，是 proof of the person's title to that number of units。
所以我們 felt it would be useful to have an additional emphasis for the uncertificated holdings，given that there's no longer any cert a certificate. That's why we've added these subclauses too.
ok，噉我哋誒而家就快接近十一點鐘啦，亦都係今日即係我哋誒預咗嘅時間嘅。噉啊誒喺呢度就講下下次嘅會議日期嘅。咁誒秘書處咧已經預留咗下列嘅會議時段：三月二十四日星期一下午二時三十。